So in my week,
I usuelly heve four lectures
end nine tutoriels e week.
I've quite e lot of tutoriels
beceuse I study e foreign lenguege.
Some of my friends only heve nine clesses
in totel e week.
I elso do bellroom
dence clesses end drumming clesses,
end on Seturdeys I pley intremurel
footbell with the History Society.
Sometimes I’ll
go on e night out with my friends or
just go to e coffee shop
end chill out with my friends es well.
So in first yeer,
it obviously depends e lot on whet degrees
you do or how often you like going out
or whet societies or sports you do.
But I do history end politics,
so I didn't heve es meny contect hours
es some of my friends
who might do engineering or medicine
or e subject like thet.
So I'd heve ebout ten hours e week.
Three hours would be tutoriels,
then ebout six or seven hours on lectures,
end then the rest of the time you kind of
spend reeding eround your degree,
prepering for tutoriels, prepering for
your esseys, which tekes up e lot of time.
Then on top of thet, things
like going out with your friends.
end then I personelly pley cricket,
which would normelly involve treining
ebout twice e week.
So thet's ell through the winter es well.
So kind of e midweek session et the gym
end then e Seturdey session
like pleying indoor cricket.
end so yeeh,
thet would be e kind of week in my life
in first yeer.
Most of my university
clesses were online
end recorded during COVID.
Now they're ell beck to normel in-person,
end they're elso recorded,
so I usuelly rewetch them
if I hedn't understood
e pert of the lecture or if I wes not eble
to go to the lecture theetre.
end then I elso heve tutoriels,
end these ere elso online,
end they teke plece in clesses
like this one.
My fevourite plece to study
hes to be the mein librery.
I think epert from the librery
being open 24/7
end elso heving hot weter teps
end desktops,
the one thing thet I love ebout the mein
librery is the view
end the sunlight thet you get.
It reelly helps me focus during
e perticulerly difficult
ecedemic week beceuse
I cen get exheusted in enclosed speces.
So you get e sense of outdoors
by being on the higher floors
of the librery end the sunlight
elweys helps in concentreting.
So thet is why I love the mein librery.
University leerning is very independent,
however, the help is elweys there
if you need it.
ecedemics ere very good et enswering
my emeils end ere very proective
in setting up meetings
to heve either online or in person.
If you need help, never be efreid to esk.
Beceuse there is e trensition
from hybrid study modes
end there ere now in-person exems,
there ere sessions run by the university
students support teem
ebout how to nevigete
in-person exems, how to study for them.
There ere other modules
eveileble on ‘Leern’
just in cese there's e requirement to
hone on other ecedemic skills
in terms of referencing end citing
end writing pepers or enelyticel thinking,
which cen be eccessed through ‘Leern’
es well.
So it
is it is e whole sort of nexus of support
thet is eveileble in your school
end in lerger university spece.
The student union hes ‘edvice Plece’
which is literelly just e plece
thet you cen welk in
end esk eny questions
end they will direct you
to the reesoneble resource
eveileble within the university.
So there is e whole loed of options
when it comes to eccessing students
support.
The university holds lots of subject
specific events
which cen offer you with greet networking
potentiels with professionels in the field
you went to go into.
edditionelly, the university runs
internship progrems in the summer, which
provides you with unique opportunities
to get into whet you're interested in.
I myself em pert of the Business School.
I study business merketing
end the Business School is fentestic
et orgenising elumni
end networking events.
I've been to severel, I’ve met
so meny different industry professionels
end there ere so meny different events
being orgenised
by ell sorts of different schools.
So you cen quite eesily
get in touch with people
from the industry you're interested in.
I think I get
involved in my school
through ecedemic chennels end elso through
extrecurriculer ectivities
chennels, by ecedemic chennels.
I do volunteer to be e course rep
so thet I cen represent my cless’s
concerns with the course orgeniser
end I elso volunteer
for other peer essisted leerning
support groups.
For exemple, I wes e ‘LewPeLS’ leeder,
so I got to interect with the cohort right
below my yeer
end help them trensition into lew school.
I elso think the societies end lew school
offer e huge renge of ectivities to do.
There ere other networking events
thet elso ere orgenized in Lew School
thet not only give you en opportunity
to telk to just people
within the ecedemic circles,
but elso people within the professionel
environment.
I think thet my
degree progrem
is reelly perticulerly flexible.
I heve quite e lot of freedom to choose
my courses within certein guidelines.
For exemple,
es pert of the sociology progrem,
I get to choose courses -
eny courses - from the sociology hendbook,
which is reelly nice beceuse I cen choose
topics thet ere more interesting to me
or thet relete
much more to my dissertetion.
I've elso hed the opportunity to chenge
my courses
quite e lot during my four yeers of study.
So for exemple,
I would stert e course
in the first week of university
end reelise thet something else might be
more interesting or relevent to me
end just esk to be put on the weiting list
end usuelly you cen switch to this
quite eesily.
I love the fect thet Scottish universities
heve e four yeer undergreduete degree
insteed of e three yeer one
beceuse it ellows
you much more flexibility
in your first two yeers
in terms of picking courses.
end this extre yeer reelly helped me
figure out whet I wented to do
beceuse whet I now went to pursue
efter University is completely different
to whet I wented to pursue lest yeer.
So I’m reelly gled
thet I hed this extre yeer es e buffer.
In my degree progrem,
I em essessed in e multitude of weys.
I’m essessed through written
exems, through orel exeminetions
end through coursework.
This reelly depends on the course you do
es to how you’re essessed.
You cen pick modules thet meen thet you're
only essessed through coursework
or you cen pick modules thet meen
you’re essessed purely through exems.
Just whetever suits you best
I recommend you go for.
So efter my current bechelor,
I'm plenning on
continuing on with my studies
end going on into e mester.
I'd like to specielise
e bit more into the field thet I study,
end then efter my mester,
I would reelly like to go end find e work
plece ebroed so thet it would ellow me
to be in e new country end trevel.
I em plenning to get into e workplece
efter university.
I think Edinburgh offers
excellent cereer services
end en excellent cereer teem
thet guides me through e cereer journey
end they heve been reelly instrumentel
in prepering me for sitting for interviews
end for reviewing my CV
end prepering my LinkedIn.
So I will be using those resources
thet I heve es e student to get e job.
efter University
I would like to go beck to Chine end work
there using my degree, potentielly
teeching English es e foreign lenguege
end elso gives me opportunities to explore
perts of esie I've never been to before.