So in my week,
I usually have four lectures
and nine tutorials a week.
I've quite a lot of tutorials
because I study a foreign language.
Some of my friends only have nine classes
in total a week.
I also do ballroom
dance classes and drumming classes,
and on Saturdays I play intramural
football with the History Society.
Sometimes I’ll
go on a night out with my friends or
just go a coffee shop
and chill out with my friends as well.
So in first year,
it obviously depends a lot on what degrees
you do or how often you like going out
or what societies or sports you do.
But I do history and politics,
so I didn't have as many contact hours
as some of my friends
who might do engineering or medicine
or a subject like that.
So I'd have about ten hours a week.
Three hours would be tutorials,
then about six or seven hours on lectures,
and then the rest of the time you kind of
spend reading around your degree,
preparing for tutorials, preparing for
your essays, which takes up a lot of time.
Then on top of that, things
like going out with your friends.
And then I personally play cricket,
which would normally involve training
about twice a week.
So that's all through the winter as well.
So kind of a midweek session at the gym
and then a Saturday session
like playing indoor cricket.
And so yeah,
that would be a kind of week in my life
in first year.
Most of my university
classes were online
and recorded during COVID.
Now they're all back normal in-person,
and they're also recorded,
so I usually rewatch them
if I hadn't understood
a part of the lecture or if I was not able
go the lecture theatre.
And then I also have tutorials,
and these are also online,
and they take place in classes
like this one.
My favourite place study
has be the main library.
I think apart from the library
being open 24/7
and also having hot water taps
and desktops,
the one thing that I love about the main
library is the view
and the sunlight that you get.
It really helps me focus during
a particularly difficult
academic week because
I can get exhausted in enclosed spaces.
So you get a sense of outdoors
by being on the higher floors
of the library and the sunlight
always helps in concentrating.
So that is why I love the main library.
University learning is very independent,
however, the help is always there
if you need it.
Academics are very good at answering
my emails and are very proactive
in setting up meetings
have either online or in person.
If you need help, never be afraid ask.
Because there is a transition
from hybrid study modes
and there are now in-person exams,
there are sessions run by the university
students support team
about how navigate
in-person exams, how study for them.
There are other modules
available on ‘Learn’
just in case there's a requirement to
hone on other academic skills
in terms of referencing and citing
and writing papers or analytical thinking,
which can be accessed through ‘Learn’
as well.
So it
is it is a whole sort of nexus of support
that is available in your school
and in larger university space.
The student union has ‘Advice Place’
which is literally just a place
that you can walk in
and ask any questions
and they will direct you
the reasonable resource
available within the university.
So there is a whole load of options
when it comes accessing students
support.
The university holds lots of subject
specific events
which can offer you with great networking
potentials with professionals in the field
you want go into.
Additionally, the university runs
internship programs in the summer, which
provides you with unique opportunities
get inwhat you're interested in.
I myself am part of the Business School.
I study business marketing
and the Business School is fantastic
at organising alumni
and networking events.
I've been several, I’ve met
so many different industry professionals
and there are so many different events
being organised
by all sorts of different schools.
So you can quite easily
get in touch with people
from the industry you're interested in.
I think I get
involved in my school
through academic channels and also through
extracurricular activities
channels, by academic channels.
I do volunteer be a course rep
so that I can represent my class’s
concerns with the course organiser
and I also volunteer
for other peer assisted learning
support groups.
For example, I was a ‘LawPALS’ leader,
so I got interact with the cohort right
below my year
and help them transition inlaw school.
I also think the societies and law school
offer a huge range of activities do.
There are other networking events
that also are organized in Law School
that not only give you an opportunity
talk just people
within the academic circles,
but also people within the professional
environment.
I think that my
degree program
is really particularly flexible.
I have quite a lot of freedom choose
my courses within certain guidelines.
For example,
as part of the sociology program,
I get choose courses -
any courses - from the sociology handbook,
which is really nice because I can choose
topics that are more interesting me
or that relate
much more my dissertation.
I've also had the opportunity change
my courses
quite a lot during my four years of study.
So for example,
I would start a course
in the first week of university
and realise that something else might be
more interesting or relevant me
and just ask be put on the waiting list
and usually you can switch this
quite easily.
I love the fact that Scottish universities
have a four year undergraduate degree
instead of a three year one
because it allows
you much more flexibility
in your first two years
in terms of picking courses.
And this extra year really helped me
figure out what I wanted do
because what I now want pursue
after University is completely different
what I wanted pursue last year.
So I’m really glad
that I had this extra year as a buffer.
In my degree program,
I am assessed in a multitude of ways.
I’m assessed through written
exams, through oral examinations
and through coursework.
This really depends on the course you do
as how you’re assessed.
You can pick modules that mean that you're
only assessed through coursework
or you can pick modules that mean
you’re assessed purely through exams.
Just whatever suits you best
I recommend you go for.
So after my current bachelor,
I'm planning on
continuing on with my studies
and going on ina master.
I'd like specialise
a bit more inthe field that I study,
and then after my master,
I would really like go and find a work
place abroad so that it would allow me
be in a new country and travel.
I am planning get ina workplace
after university.
I think Edinburgh offers
excellent career services
and an excellent career team
that guides me through a career journey
and they have been really instrumental
in preparing me for sitting for interviews
and for reviewing my CV
and preparing my LinkedIn.
So I will be using those resources
that I have as a student get a job.
After University
I would like go back China and work
there using my degree, potentially
teaching English as a foreign language
and also gives me opportunities explore
parts of Asia I've never been before.